<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20230515</CreaDate><CreaTime>14243200</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><DataProperties><lineage><Process ToolSource="c:\program files\arcgis\pro\Resources\ArcToolbox\toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\Project" Date="20230515" Time="142432">Project "C:\Users\msorlien\OneDrive - NBEP - RWU\Documents\GIS_PROJECTS\INTERNAL_PROJECTS\EJ_map_v2\EJmap_prep\gis_data\int_gisdata\ejmap_intdata.gdb\EJMETRICS_2022_LOWRES_NBEP2023" "C:\Users\msorlien\OneDrive - NBEP - RWU\Documents\GIS_PROJECTS\INTERNAL_PROJECTS\EJ_map_v2\EJmap\data-raw\EJMETRICS_2022_LOWRES_NBEP2023.shp" GEOGCS["GCS_WGS_1984",DATUM["D_WGS_1984",SPHEROID["WGS_1984",6378137.0,298.257223563]],PRIMEM["Greenwich",0.0],UNIT["Degree",0.0174532925199433]] WGS_1984_(ITRF00)_To_NAD_1983 PROJCS["NAD_1983_UTM_Zone_19N",GEOGCS["GCS_North_American_1983",DATUM["D_North_American_1983",SPHEROID["GRS_1980",6378137.0,298.257222101]],PRIMEM["Greenwich",0.0],UNIT["Degree",0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION["Transverse_Mercator"],PARAMETER["False_Easting",500000.0],PARAMETER["False_Northing",0.0],PARAMETER["Central_Meridian",-69.0],PARAMETER["Scale_Factor",0.9996],PARAMETER["Latitude_Of_Origin",0.0],UNIT["Meter",1.0]] NO_PRESERVE_SHAPE # NO_VERTICAL</Process><Process ToolSource="c:\program files\arcgis\pro\Resources\ArcToolbox\toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\DeleteField" Date="20230516" Time="090552">DeleteField EJMETRICS_2022_LOWRES_NBEP2023 OBJECTID "Delete Fields"</Process><Process ToolSource="c:\program files\arcgis\pro\Resources\ArcToolbox\toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\DeleteField" Date="20230516" Time="090630">DeleteField EJMETRICS_2022_LOWRES_NBEP2023 Shape_Leng "Delete Fields"</Process><Process ToolSource="c:\program files\arcgis\pro\Resources\ArcToolbox\toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\DeleteField" Date="20230516" Time="090635">DeleteField EJMETRICS_2022_LOWRES_NBEP2023 Shape_Area "Delete Fields"</Process></lineage></DataProperties></Esri><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>EJMETRICS_2022_NBEP2023</resTitle></idCitation><searchKeys><keyword>environmental justice</keyword><keyword>underserved areas</keyword><keyword>population vulnerability</keyword><keyword>social vulnerability</keyword><keyword>environmental risk susceptibility</keyword><keyword>EJSCREEN</keyword><keyword>population demographics</keyword><keyword>people</keyword></searchKeys><idPurp>Environmental justice metrics in the Narragansett Bay region derived from the U.S. EPA (EPA) EJSCREEN dataset (EPA 2022). This dataset is intended for general planning, graphic display, and GIS analysis.</idPurp><idAbs>Environmental justice metrics in the Narragansett Bay region derived from the U.S. EPA (EPA) EJSCREEN dataset (EPA 2022). EJSCREEN provides population demographics and other information at the U.S. Census "block group" scale (American Community Survey 2020). EJSCREEN data was supplemented with data from the U.S. Center for Disease Control and Prevention PLACES estimate, the National Landcover Database, the First Street Foundation, and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration. This data is intended for general planning, graphic display, and GIS analysis.</idAbs><idCredit>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency Environmental Justice Screening and Mapping Tool (EJSCREEN); U.S. Center for Disease Control and Prevention PLACES estimate; National Land Cover Database; First Street Foundation; NOAA; Narragansett Bay Estuary Program</idCredit><resConst><Consts><useLimit>This dataset is provided "as is". The producer(s) of this dataset, contributors to this dataset, and the Narragansett Bay Estuary Program (NBEP) do not make any warranties of any kind for this dataset, and are not liable for any loss or damage however and whenever caused by any use of this dataset. This data is provided under the Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International (CC BY-NC-SA 4.0) license. Once acquired, any modification made to the data must be noted in the metadata. Please acknowledge both NBEP and the primary producer(s) of this dataset or any derived products. These data are intended for use as a tool for reference, display, and general GIS analysis purposes only. It is the responsibility of the data user to use the data appropriately and consistent with the limitations of geospatial data in general and these data in particular. The information contained in these data may be dynamic and could change over time. The data accuracy is checked against best available sources which may be dated. The data are not better than the original sources from which they are derived. These data are not designed for use as a primary regulatory tool in permitting or siting decisions and are not a legally authoritative source for the location of natural or manmade features. The depicted boundaries, interpretations, and analysis derived from have not been verified at the site level them and do not eliminate the need for onsite sampling, testing, and detailed study of specific sites. This project was funded by agreements by the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to Roger Williams University (RWU) in partnership with the Narragansett Bay Estuary Program. Although the information in this document has been funded wholly or in part by EPA under the agreements CE00A00967 to RWU, it has not undergone the Agency’s publications review process and therefore, may not necessarily reflect the views of the Agency and no official endorsement should be inferred. The viewpoints expressed here do not necessarily represent those of the Narragansett Bay Estuary Program, RWU, or EPA nor does mention of trade names, commercial products, or causes constitute endorsement or recommendation for use.</useLimit></Consts></resConst></dataIdInfo></metadata>
